Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/siddharthdixit-76802915b (LinkedIn) sid-darthvader.github.io (Personal)

Top Skills

Machine Learning
Predictive Modeling
Deep Learning

Certifications

Introduction to Data Visualization with Seaborn

Introduction to Deep Learning in Python

Python Data Science Toolbox (Part-I)

Introduction to Importing Data in Python

Intermediate Importing Data in Python

Honors-Awards

Runner up, Dot Tech category, Hackdata 2018

Vice Chancellors Funding

Publications

Network Learning Approaches to study World Happiness

Get Bristol moving: tackling air pollution in Bristol city centre

Machine Learning approaches to Identify and Design Low Thermal Conductivity Oxide Alloys for Thermoelectric Applications

Siddharth Dixit

Data Scientist @ Noodle.ai Bangalore Urban

Summary

Data scientist with a background in Applied Mathematics, who is passionate about solving business problems using Machine Learning.

My areas of research lie in Predictive Modelling, Statistical Machine Learning and more recently Causal Inference. Previously, I have conducted research on their applications in diverse areas such as Materials Informatics, Environmental Sciences and Computational Social Sciences.

In my free time, I also enjoy writing blogs on using Machine Learning to solve business problems (https://medium.com/@sid_darthvader).

For finer details and more recent updates, please visit my website (https://sid-darthvader.github.io) or drop me a message!

Experience

Noodle.ai

8 months

Data Scientist

June 2022 - Present (2 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Working as a Data Scientist within the Supply Chain AI (SCAI) unit.

Associate Data Scientist

December 2021 - June 2022 (7 months)

Bangalore Urban, Karnataka, India

- As a part of the Manufacturing Asset Health AI team, I worked with a major steel manufacturer to reduce unplanned equipment downtime across multiple equipments by deploying time-series: Time to Failure & Anomaly Detection models.

My daily responsibilities included understanding different use-cases, framing problem statements and delivering client presentations on Exploratory

Data Analysis on sensor behaviour, deployment of models for multiple subcomponents and post deployment analysis of model predictions.

- Researched and developed an innovative AutoML for Predictive Maintenance that improved upon the existing Time-to-failure & Anomaly Detection models in terms of scalability and accuracy across several use-cases.
- Supervised an intern within our team that worked with us on testing out the innovative AutoML for Predictive Maintenance described above on multiple client use-cases.

Freadom (Stones2Milestones)
Manager-Data Science
August 2021 - November 2021 (4 months)
Gurugram, Haryana, India

Worked with an Ed-tech startup on product Data Science use cases to improve the following KPI's for a 300K user base:

- New User Acquisition: KPI- Lead Conversions

- User Engagement : KPI- Average Time Spent

- User Retention: KPI- Daily Active Users

University of Leeds
Visiting Researcher
July 2021 - August 2021 (2 months)
Leeds, England, United Kingdom

Project: Vet-Al Clinical team rota conundrum: Predicting demand

Vet-Al is a tech company that is making animal care more accessible and affordable with a remote veterinary care app that gives pet owners access to professional veterinary advice.

In this challenge, I worked with a team of 9 researchers to develop a forecasting model that could be used to staff vets and nurses working in the app over a 24-hour period, according to variables like the previous usage of the app, the day of the week, the number of users and pets, among others.

causaLens
Data Scientist (Intern)
December 2020 - June 2021 (7 months)

London, England, United Kingdom

Data Scientist focused on the Innovative Applications of Causal ML:

- Worked as an intern with the Marketing & Applied Data Science (ADS) teams.
- Researched and developed innovative business use-cases for Causal ML in Banking, Marketing, Insurance, Telecommunications, E-commerce & Retail, Manufacturing & IoT, Transport & Logistics, and other industries.
- Carried out proof-of-concept data science work for:
- 1) Credit Risk Modeling in SME Lending
- 2) Predictive Lead Scoring for B2B businesses
- Assisted ADS with data science work for client projects
- Suggested improvements to core product by reviewing the latest research on Causal ML

Shiv Nadar University
Teaching Assistant- Deep Learning
August 2020 - November 2020 (4 months)
Delhi, India

- Co-taught MAT-494: Deep Learning to 3rd & 4th-year undergrads at Shiv Nadar University.
- Conducted lab sessions in R & Python with a focus on solving business problems using Predictive Modeling.
- Supervised 7 student projects on using Deep Learning to solve problems in Healthcare, Banking, Asset Management&CRM.

SNU.ai Co-Founder November 2019 - October 2020 (1 year) India

- I was appointed by the Director of Research, SNU to start a club that specifically focuses on AI research and its applications to different domains.
- Over a year, I mentored ~ 100 undergrads from different majors to learn ML
 and apply it to research projects within their field of interest.
- Organized talks and webinars with industry experts and researchers in the AI/ ML space.

University of Luxembourg
Visiting Research Scholar
March 2020 - March 2020 (1 month)

Belval Campus, Luxembourg

- A part of the Legato Team of Prof. Stephane Bordas doing research on Physics Informed Deep Learning in the area of Biomechanics.
- During my time there I studied about different Neural Network architectures used to solve and discover both Ordinary and Partial Differential Equations related to physics.

The Alan Turing Institute
Data Study group participant
August 2019 - August 2019 (1 month)

Bristol, United Kingdom

Worked on the 'Air pollution in Bristol City Center' project given to our team at the Turing Data Study group organized by the Alan Turing Institute, Jean Golding Institute and the Bristol City Council. I worked on linking the Weather data and the Air pollution data to build different models and generate insights which could be then acted upon by the Bristol City Council to reduce air pollution in the Bristol City Center.

Education

Shiv Nadar University

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics(Minor-Computer Science) specialization in Artificial Intelligence · (January 2017 - May 2021)

City Montessori School

· (July 2014 - July 2016)

St Francis College Lucknow

· (July 2002 - July 2014)